杰森:你还好吧?
Jason: You ok?
麦琪:哦,我很好.只是一幢房子而已.
Maggie: Oh I'm fine, it's just a house.
杰森:是的.这是你这辈子前18年居住的那幢房子.
Jason: Yea, it's just a house that you lived in for the first 18 years
自从你父亲去世你还一直没来过呢.
of your life, house that you haven' even seen since your dad died.
麦琪:我说了,只是一幢房子.哦,上帝.这是爸爸坐的椅子.
Maggie: Like I said, it's just a house.Oh my God its daddy's chair.
杰森:我告诉他我们要结婚的时候,他就是坐在这把椅子上的.
Jason: That's the very one he was sitting in when I told him we were
getting married
麦琪:他气坏了.
Maggie: He got so mad.
杰森:哦,是的.他一直对此耿耿与怀.
Jason: Oh yea, guess he never did get that fixed.
迈克:好了.过来.
Mike: Ok come here.
开萝尔:看啊,我们在这里曾玩过牛仔和印第安人的游戏呢.
Carol: And look, this is where we use to play cowboys and Indians,
我扮演印第安少女,美丽而充满自信.
I was the Indian maiden beautiful yet entirely self reliant.
本:是的.我还记得你印第安的名字叫"部落弃儿".
Ben: Yea, I still remember your Indian name 'abandon by tribe'.
开萝尔:谢谢你提醒我,"与洋娃娃共眠".
Carol: Thanks for reminding us 'sleeps with the doll' .
迈克:我记得外公一直这个样子,眼睛一眨一眨,
Mike: This is how I remember granps,
豪爽地笑着.
with the twinkling eyes and the corky grin.
杰森:虚荣,自得,自满,哦,我想他.
Jason: Vain, smug, self-satisfied, I miss him .
迈克:啊,我喜欢这个房子.
Mike: Aw I love this house .
克莉丝:我也是.让我感觉回到了童年.
Chrissie: Me too, makes me feel like a kid again .
杰森:好了,孩子们别在回想了.
Jason: Well don't you guys get to attached remember we were here to help
我们来是帮助外婆修理房子,然后买掉的.
grandma fix this house up so she can sell it .
克莉丝:可为什么外婆要搬走呢?
Chrissie: But why does grandma have to move?
佛罗里达更温暖,而且这房子对一个人来说太大了.
Maggie: Florida is warmer besides this house is too big for one person.
本:开萝尔可以回来跟外婆住.
Ben: Carol could come live with grandma.
迈克:本,外婆已经失去丈夫了,你还嫌她不痛苦吗?
Mike: Ben grandma just lost her husband hasn't she being through enough.
杰森:哦,对了,外婆呢?
Jason: By the way where is grandma?
开萝尔:她没进来吗?
Carol: Didn't she come in?
麦琪:妈妈,进来好吗?
Maggie: Mom, are you coming in?
外婆:我应该待在阿克伦你路易丝姨妈家好了.
Grandma: I should have stayed in Akron with your aunt Louise she didn't
她不会让我做艰难的决定.
ask me to make tough decisions.
麦琪:哦,别这样,
Maggie: Come on mom,
妈妈.
I know you haven't been here since the funeral but we need you to help
我知道爸爸葬礼以后你还没来过呢,但我们需要你帮着整理东西啊.
sort thing out.
外婆:我真想再看看你父亲进门来的样子.这里只剩下鬼魂了.
Grandma: I almost spent see you father through the door.Just so many ghost here.
克莉丝:鬼魂?
Chrissy: Ghost?
麦琪:宝贝,这只是打比方.
Maggie: Honey it's just a figure of speech.
杰森:世上根本没有鬼魂的.
Jason: There is no such things as ghost.
外公:你知道的真不少,傻女婿.
Grandpa: A lot you know shrink man.
外公:哦,凯蒂,我的好宝贝,
Grandpa: Oh Katie my girl you look even more lovely than I remember,
你比我想的还要可爱的多.但我只说一件事,你那聪明的脑瓜是不是不活动了.
but I just got one thing to say, you lose you god inpicken mind,
我听说这里麻烦事不少,你要把房子给卖了,
I mean I heard there was trouble here but selling our house and then some 40
连同将近40年的记忆.哦,我正在跟一个只知道磨速溶咖啡的女人说话.
odd years of memory, I'm talking to a woman who is grinding instant coffee.
麦琪:好了,听着,
Maggie: Ok everybody listen up, tonight grandma Kate sleeps in her room,
今晚外婆睡自己的卧室,我和你爸爸谁客房,其他人都睡在这里.
your dad and I have the guest room and the rest of you sleeps down here.
这里?你想让6个人一起睡在折叠沙发上?
Ben: Here?You expect 6 people to share a fold up couch.
卢克:嘿,嘿,我睡地板,这就像野外宿营一样,只是在屋里.
Luke: Hey hey, the floors find with me it's like camping out only it's in.
外公:这个小子是谁?谁告诉我他的名字?
Grandpa: Who is the tall head here?Well could somebody at least tell me his name.
开萝尔:卢克说的对.
Carol: I agree with Luke
外公:非常感谢.
Grandpa: Thank you very much.
开萝尔:我睡什么地方都行,
Carol: I could sleep anywhere as long as it's not in smelling distance
只要闻不到本的臭脚丫就好.
from Ben's feet.
迈克:哦,我想开萝尔只能到外边睡了.
Mike: Oh I guess Carol is sleeping outside.
外婆:谁要想和我一起睡那个大床,我都欢迎.
Grandma: Someone is welcome to sleep in that big bed with me,
即使你,本,谁也比不上你外公那双臭脚的.
even you Ben nothing could be worst than your grandfather's feet.
外公:嘿,我是一天巡逻8小时的警察,
Grandpa: Hey I was a cop walking an 8 hour bet what do you except,
你能期望什么,玫瑰花香吗?
rose petals.
麦琪:谢谢您的关心,妈妈,但您需要睡的舒服点,这是您的房子.
Maggie: Thanks for the offer mom but you need some privacy this is your house.
杰森:我列了个修理单子,修完之后我们才能卖房子.
Jason: I have a list of repair we have to do before we can sell this house.
外公:谁死了让你在这里管事了.哦,是我.
Grandpa: Who died and put you in charge, oh I guess I did.
为了这个,你们就把我从天堂叫过来,我还有高尔夫比赛没打完呢.
For this you called me out of a golf game with James Mansfield and Scoraties.
凯特:你们知道我为什么不给你们做午饭.
Kate: You know why don't I fix lunch for everybody.
开萝尔:你还能做午饭吗,还是我来吧.
Carol: The human granola bar is cooking lunch, I better take over.
卢克:开萝尔要做午饭了.来吧,克莉丝,我们去叫比萨吃去.
Luke: Carol's cooking lunch, come on Chrissie let's go call for pizza.
外婆:本,你愿意挣两美元吗?帮你老外婆搬搬这几个箱子.
Grandma: Benny you want to earn a couple of dollars helping your old grandma carry some boxes?
本:当然了,可我还是愿意免费帮您的.
Ben: Sure, but if course I'd rather carry them for free.
凯特:开萝尔真是个好姑娘.
Kate: Carol is such a nice person,
她走进厨房说我是客人,
she comes into the kitchen says I'm a guest and she refused to let me
说什么也不让我做午饭.
cook lunch.
迈克:我也希望是她来做这顿饭.
Mike: Well it's times like this when I love her to.
杰森:好了,迈克,能过来帮我清理这些水沟吗?
Jason: Alright Mike I could use your help cleaning out those rain gutters.
迈克:哦,啊,当然了,爸爸.
Mike: Oh ah, sure dad.
凯特:哦,迈克,你还好吗?
Kate: Oh Mike are you ok?
杰森:怎么了?
Jason: What happened?
迈克:我扭着脚踝了.我不知道还能不能帮你忙了,
Mike: It's my ankle I twisted it,
爸爸.
I don't know if I could handle those gutters dad.
真的?有那么严重吗?
Jason: Really?Isn't that convenient.
外公:哦,你这个铁石心肠的人.
Grandpa: Oh you cold hearted quack.
凯特:西沃医生,你儿子受伤了.
Kate: Doctor Sever your son is hurt.
迈克:不,不,不,这没什么,只是不能走路了.扶我到梯子那里.
Mike: No no no, it's nothing that I can't walk of, let me at that ladder.
杰森:哦,好吧.
Jason: Oh alright, maybe I was hasty Mike maybe Kate should take you to
也许我太急了.迈克,让凯特带你去拍个片子吧.
get that x-ray.
迈克:那好吧,既然你这么说.
Mike: Well alright if you say so.
杰森:因为你过去老骗我,对不起.
Jason: Just that you pull so many scams in the past I, I'm sorry.
迈克:好了..
Mike: Ok.
外公:怎么了,你这个小滑头.
Grandpa: Why you little scam.
凯特:你干什么呢?
Kate: What are you doing?
迈克:我们今天可以去逛逛波士顿了.
Mike: I am getting us a day of sightseeing in Boston.
凯特:你没受伤吗?
Kate: You're not hurt?
迈克:如果我真的受伤了,还能这样吗?
Mike: Well if I was do you think I could do this.
外公:是我教的.
Grandpa: I taught him that.
凯特:迈克肺魑郑愀詹畔诺奈野胨馈?
Kate: Mike Sever you scared me half to death.
迈克:我知道,凯特,
Mike: I know, I know Kate but I had to,
但我只能这么做.我一个人是不能蒙混过去的.
I mean I couldn't put of this lame scam all by myself.
凯特:哦,所以你也欺骗了我.
Kate: Oh so you made me your Patsy.
迈克:哦,不.实际上上当的是爸爸,你只是我的帮凶.
Mike: Well no technically dad was the pasty and you were my stooge.
凯特:你什么时候才能长大啊?
Kate: When are you going to grow up?
外公:女人呐.
Grandpa: Women.
杰森:嘿,我还以为你们去急救室了呢.
Jason: Hi I though you were going to the emergency room.
迈克:爸爸,我不在乎我有多么疼,
Mike: Dad look I don't care how bad the pain is I'm going to help you
我打算帮你清理水沟.
with those gutters.
杰森:哦,我知道了.凯特不想逛街.
Jason: Oh I see Kate didn't want to go sightseeing.
本:天啊,这箱子真沉.
Ben: Gosh this box is heavy.
外婆:这里,本,别告诉你妈妈.
Grandma: Here Ben, don't tell your mother.
麦琪:妈妈,我就站在这里呢.
Maggie: Mom I'm standing right here.
外婆:别乱说.
Grandma: Big mouth.
麦琪:妈妈,你就那么点储蓄,
Maggie: Mom you are on a fixed income you can't keep giving your money
你不能老让本这个小家伙敲你的竹杠啊.
away to an extortionist.
外婆:我不知道本是个勒索鬼啊.
Grandma: I didn't know Ben was double-jointed.
麦琪:整理一下吧,这些东西都要带到公寓里去吗?
Maggie: Let's get to it, only so much will fit in your condo.
外婆:哦,我就是害怕收拾东西,不知道什么该留下,什么该扔了.
Grandma: Oh I'm awful at this I never know to save and what to throw away.
麦琪:你看,这个可以扔了吧,你的老式榨汁机.
Maggie: Well here's you can throw away, your old fashion juicer.
外婆:哦,不,我要去佛罗里达,还能用得着.
Grandma: Oh no, I'm going to Florida I'll need that.
麦琪:哦,妈妈,你楼下还有个电动的呢.
Maggie: Well mom you've got an electric juicer downstairs.
外婆:我从没用过那个.
Grandma: I never used that one.
麦琪:为什么?
Maggie: Why not?
外婆:我讨厌喝橙汁.
Grandma: I hate orange juice.
外公:可我忍受了46年.
grandpa: See what I put up with for 46 years .
开萝尔:这里有几个纸箱,啊,是魔法城堡.
Carol: I brought some boxes, aww the enchanted castle .
外公:你知道什么,这是我二战时用的小帐篷.
Grandpa: Oh what do you know my old WW2 pumpkin.
开萝尔:我跟外公经常玩这个游戏.我扮演公主,外公扮演勇敢的骑士.恐怖的魔龙来了,他要杀死它.
Carol: Grandpa and I use to play this game where I was the princess and
grandpa was the gallant knight who has to slay the dragon with the horrible breath
迈克就是那条魔龙.
otherwise know as Mike.
外婆:哦,看杰森在那里.
Grandma: Oh look there's Jason.
麦琪:杰森,水沟修的怎样了?
Maggie: Jason how are the gutters coming?
外公:要是掉下去,最好头先着地.
Grandpa: Look if you fall try to land on your hair.
杰森:好了,迈克,先别拧开水龙头,我得…
Jason: Alright Mike don't turn that water on until I've got a...
外公:哦,看啊,他滚下去了.
Grandpa: Boy look at that kid run.
外公:玛格丽特,对不起,
Grandpa: Margaret, I'm sorry that I didn't take you on the fishing trip
我答应了你,却没有带你去钓鱼.
that I promise to.
我知道你能听到我说的话.我要很多事要做,
I know you can hear what I am talking to.
就是为了弥补对你的愧疚.
But you see, I have long checklist things to my apologize for...
外公:我已经做了2件了.还有3163件.
Grandpa: Well that's 2 done and ah 3163 to go.
外公:听着,我有许多抱歉的话有说.在婚礼上,我竟然骂你是粗壮的菠菜,大傻瓜.
Grandpa: Listen I got some apologies to make to you to, at that time at
your wedding when I called you a bustering spinach for brains nincomepoop
对不起.不,我没有.这是谁写的?
I'm sorry no I'm not who wrote this?
杰森:我要把那扇纱窗安回原处.
Jason: I'm going to go knock that window screen back into place.
迈克:哦,看啊,这些都是外公给外婆写的情书.
Mike: Oh look at all these letters that grandma saved from grandpa
外公:女人总喜欢留着一切东西.
Grandpa: Woman doesn't throw out anything.
迈克:那是什么?
Mike: What was that?
麦琪:你父亲.
Maggie: Your father.
迈克:哦,哇,不可思议.
Mike: Oh wow this is incredible.
外公:什么,哦,不能读.这是私人信件.
Grandpa: What, oh don't read that, that's private.
迈克:最亲爱的凯蒂…
Mike: My dearest Katie.
外公:年轻人,总是不听话.
Grandpa: Young people they never listen.
麦琪:杰森,我们是不是雇一些人来做这些事呢?
Maggie: Jason shouldn't we hire someone to make these repairs?
杰森:不是我的错.我举锤子的时候吸进一只虫子.
Jason: It wasn't my fault, I was swing the hammer I inhaled a moth.
迈克,上楼拿纱布和杀菌剂下来.
Maggie: Mike go upstairs and get a bandage and antiseptic.
杰森:还有胃药.
Jason: And Maalox.
迈克:好的.
Mike: Sure.
麦琪:哦,杰森,我只能跟你一个人说,
Maggie: Oh Jason, now that I have you alone I'm so worried about my mother
我非常担心妈妈,她说话含糊不清,迷茫而慌乱.
she seems vague, indecisive, confused.
杰森:好像脱离了现实世界,是吗?
Jason: Totally out of touch with reality?
麦琪:你也注意到了.
Maggie: You've noticed it too.
杰森:从1968年起就这样了.
Jason: Since 1968.
麦琪:不,杰森,这次最为严重.
Maggie: No Jason this is worst than usual.
杰森:亲爱的,她只是思念埃德而已.你得顺着她.
Jason: Honey she's grieving over Ed you've got to bear with her.
麦琪:哦,我一直这样.可她让我实在难过.感谢上帝,她要搬到佛罗里达了.很明显,她一个人很难料理这幢房子.
Maggie: Oh I'm trying but she is really getting to me, thank God she's moving
to Florida it's obvious she can't handle this house by herself
杰森:哦,还没糟到这一步.
Jason: Oh it's not as bad as you think.
克莉丝:妈妈,爸爸,快点,外婆的头发夹到沙发床里了.
Chris: Mommy, daddy come quick grandma got her head stuck in the sofa bed.
本:哦,詹妮,哦,詹妮.
Ben: Oh Jenny, oh Jenny.
开萝尔:简直无法忍受跟这帮混球在一起睡觉.对了,
Carol: What made me think I could sleep with this ravel,
我要到外婆那儿陪她去.外婆.
I know I'll take grandma up on here offer, grandma.
外公:哦,可爱的小乖乖,
Grandpa: Oh my darling Katie just look at you,
我来看你了,
you still sleeping on your side of the bed,
你怎么还睡在自己那一半地方?你完全可以随意把身体伸开了.
you can spread out now if you want to you know.
哦,凯蒂,
Ah Katie what are you going to do without me,
我不在你可怎么办呢?你竟然在图片市场花20分钟想买一筐鸡崽;
the one who spends 20mins at the photo mart trying to buy a bucket of chicken,
竟然拿着一张100万元的支票去兑换现金.
the woman who tried to cash one of those million dollar Ed Mac mad checks.
凯蒂,我的宝贝,你把我都吓死了.你懂我的意思,
Katie my girl you scared me to death, well you know what I mean,
对吧.哦,我真的很想知道
all I really want to know Kate is
"你过的还好吗"?你会很好的,对吧,凯蒂.
are you going to be alright?' you are going to be alright aren't you Kate .
凯特:迈克.
Kate: Mike.
迈克:嘿,我给你看样我找到的东西.
Mike: Hey I want to show you something I found.
凯特:是你伪造的第一份成绩单吗?
Kate: What's that the first report card you foraged?
迈克:不是,这是一封外公写给外婆的情书.埃德外公写情书的时候,还是在二战时期的太平洋战场上呢.
Mike: No, is ah love letter from my grandfather to my grandmother, grandpa Ed wrote this when he was station in the pacific in world war 2.
凯特:哦.
Kate: Oh.
迈克:听我给你念一念.我最亲爱的凯蒂,
Mike: Just listen.My dearest Katie here I am on this God forsaking island
我正在一座荒凉的孤岛上,心里想的全是你.我觉得配不上你,
and all I could think about is you I don't deserve you I'm vain selfish
我自负,自私,
and
不成熟,可在枪林弹雨中我正在迅速成长.
immature, but out here with the bullets flying I'm growing up fast,
我爱你凯蒂,
I love you Kate and I pray that the lord keeps you safe so I could
我祈求上帝能保佑你平安,这样我可以回到你的身边与你相聚.
return home to your
你深爱着的士兵-埃德.
arms, your devoted solider boy Eddy.
凯特:哦,迈克,写的太感人了.
Kate: Oh Mike that's beautiful.
迈克:凯特,这封信完全说出了我的心声,
Mike: Kate this letter says what I've being trying to say to you better
这正是我一直想对你说的.
than I ever could.
凯特:哦,迈克,
Kate: Oh Mike.
迈克:哦,凯特.
Mike: Oh Kate.
开萝尔:哦,求你们了,我只是想找一个安静的地方睡一会.
Carol: Oh please, a quiet place to sleep that's all I ask.
凯特:我刚才和迈克分享了最为美好的东西,
Kate: Your son just shared the most wonderful thing with me,
是外公写给外婆的情书.
a love letter from your dad to your mom.
外公:哦,别再传播了.
Grandpa: Oh not that darn thing again.
麦琪:一封情书,我看看.
Maggie: A love letter let me see that.
外公:哦,天啊.
Grandpa: Oh boy.
凯特:写的真动人,尤其是"我正在枪淋弹雨中迅速成长"那一句.很好笑吗?
Kate: It's so beautiful, especially the part about growing up fast when the bullets are flying.What's so funny?
麦琪:这封信是编造的.
Maggie: This letter, it's a croc.
凯特:你说什么?这封信不是埃德外公写的?
Kate: What do you mean, grandpa Ed didn't write it?
麦琪:不,是他写的,但不是在太平洋上一个荒凉的孤岛上.那时他在后方的给养站,空中飞的都是奶酪和牛肉干.
Maggie: No, oh he wrote it but not form some god forsaken island in the pacific, he wrote it fro the mess hall at fort dicks the only thing that was flying
他从没出过海.在战争结束之前一小时,
was cream chip beef,
他寄出了这封信.
he never shipped out he mailed this an hour before the war ended.
外公:嘿,那是我的错吗?午饭刚结束和平就来临了.
Grandpa: Hey was it my fault that peace broke out right after lunch.
凯特:那迈克知道这事吗?
Kate: Does Mike know about all of this?
麦琪:他应该知道的.多年来,这一直是家里的一个传统笑话.
Maggie: Well he should, it's being a family joke for years.
凯特:对不起,我给炉子弄些木柴去.
Kate: Excuse me, I have to get some wood for the fire,
我现在要好好地修理修理他.
I gotta chop something now.
麦琪:哦,妈妈,
Maggie: Oh mom good I've being looking for that pile of clothes we left
我怎么也找不到放在沙发上的那堆衣服了.您知道跑哪儿去了吗?
on the couch do you know what happen to them?
外婆:什么衣服啊?
Grandma: What pile of clothes?
麦琪:我们花了一整天时间整理后放到箱子里的那一堆衣服.
Maggie: The ones we spend all day packing and putting in boxes.
外婆:把它们放回到衣柜里去了.
Grandma: Put them all back in the closet.
麦琪:你说什么?
Maggie: You did what?
外婆:你说要腾出几个空箱子装捐献给无家可归者的衣服.
Grandma: You said you needed boxes for some clothes for the homeless.
麦琪:妈妈,那就是给无家可归者的衣服啊.
Maggie: Mom those were the clothes for the homeless.
外婆:那我干嘛要把它们放回衣柜里去呢?
Grandma: Then what are they doing back in the closet?
麦琪:妈妈,您脑子怎么了?
Maggie: Mother where is your head?
外公:注意跟你妈说话的口气.你脑子怎么了?
Grandpa: Watch that tone with your mother.Where is your head?
外婆:对不起,最近,我也不知道怎么了.
Grandma: I'm sorry I don't know what's the matter with me lately.
麦琪:不怪您,妈妈,对不起我不该对您喊.我只是担心您.
Maggie: No mom I'm sorry I yelled at you I'm just worried about you .
外婆:我去拿衣服.
Grandma: I'll get the clothes.
外公:以前我冲你发火,凯蒂,你也总是走开,
Grandpa: You used to walk away from me when I yelled at you Kate,
不让我看.这就是你当时的表情,是不是?
so that's what your face looked like huh.
杰森:怎么回事儿?我在那儿都听到你喊了.
Jason: What was that all above I could hear the yelling in there.
麦琪:杰森,
Maggie: Jason I don't know what I'm going to do with my mom,
我不知道把妈妈怎么办才好了.她说要搬到佛罗里达去,
she says she want to move to Florida but by the ways she's acting you'd
可她的一举一动实在让人不放心.
never know it .
杰森:我的病人这个样子的时候,我只看他们的行动,
Jason: well if my patients behave like that I look at what there're doing
不管他们说什么.
not what they saying.
外公:哦,说的很对,
Grandpa: Oh horse hockey,
你这木头脑瓜比我想像的要聪明些.
I've seen better wisdom embroidered on a couch pillow.
杰森:嗨,卢克,过来帮我堆这些该死的木头好吗?
Jason: Hey Luke you want to help me stack some snide blocks.
卢克:哦,可以,没问题.呃,我得把药箱拿上.
Luke: Oh yea sure thing.Hmm I'll go get the medicine kit .
迈克:求你了!我发誓并不知道.
Mike: Please!I swerve I didn't know.
凯特:我凭什么要再相信你呢?
Kate: Why should I believe anything you say?
迈克:就凭你手上的家伙.哦,外婆,对不起,我要去洗洗了.
Mike: Because you're still armed.Ah grandma, excuse me I've got to go wash up.
外婆:他吃东西时总是这么邋遢.
Grandma: He was always a messy eater.
凯特:您外孙总是这么气人.
Kate: Your grandson can be so exasperating.
外婆:他脑子发育不健全.
Grandma: It's his deviated septum.
凯特:不是,我们只是在为这个吵架.
Kate: No we were fighting about this.
外公:别再这样了.我都是鬼魂了,这东西还在缠着我.
Grandpa: Not again, I'm the ghost here and this thing keeps hunting me.
外婆:许多年我都不看了.
Grandma: I haven't seen this in years.
外公:哦,又来了,因为写了这封愚蠢的信,她一直不肯原谅我.
Grandpa: Oh hear it comes, boy she's never forgiven me for writing that stupid letter
凯特:哦,真对不起,我不该给您看这个,这一定是您的心病.
Kate: Oh I'm sorry I shouldn't have shown that to you I'm sure that's a sore spot.
外公:心病,见鬼,我差点毁了我们的婚事.
Grandpa: Sore shot, hell I almost hand in our engagement.
外婆:我要告诉你一个秘密;我就是因为这封信才嫁给埃德的.
Grandma: I'll let you in on a secret; I married Ed because of this letter.
凯特和外公:呃?
Kate and Grandpa: huh?
外婆:哦,虽然他有点儿言过其实,
Grandma: Oh true he stretch the truth a bit but,
但这是他第一次说他爱我.他经历了一次世界大战才有了说爱我的勇气.
it was the first time he said he loved me,
但是对埃德这样的男人,
granted it took a world war to get him to say it but with men like
不能听他嘴上说的,而是听他的心声.
Ed you've got to look beyond the blind end listen to what your heart is
想到这儿,我就像触电一样.
saying just thinking about it gives me gooses bumps.
外公:你不是唯一的女孩.
Grandpa: You're not the only one.
凯特:我要去找迈克了.
Kate: I think I'm going to go look for Mike.
外婆:怎么了?
Grandma: What happened?
麦琪:哦,杰森让木头砸着脚趾了.
Maggie: Oh Jason dropped a snider block on his toe.
杰森:不是我掉的,是风吹的.
Jason: I didn't drop it there was gust of wind.
外公:是耳旁风吧.
Grandpa: Right between his ears.
杰森,我来给你包一下,你脚趾就不会疼了.
Maggie: Jason your toe will be fine just let me put a bandage on it.
我自己会包.
Jason: I could put a bandage on it myself.
麦琪:不,让我来.
Maggie: No let me.
杰森:麦琪,你这样对我就好像我怎么着了似的…我正要去换那扇窗户.
Jason: Maggie you're treating me like I were in a ....I was going to replace that window anyway.
麦琪:哦,过来吧.
Maggie: Oh come on.
杰森:小心脚趾.
Jason: Watch the toe.
麦琪:知道.
Maggie: Ok.
杰森:小心脚趾.
Jason: Watch the toe.
麦琪:我知道.
Maggie: I am.
卢克:我可以喝杯水吗?
Luke: Can I have a glass of water?
外婆:当然了.
Grandma: Oh sure.
卢克:看来用不着水杯了.
Luke: Ok forget the glass.
外婆:对不起,哦,真开心,我要走了,我再也管不了这房子了.
Grandma: Sorry, oh I'm glad I'm leaving I can't handle this house anymore.
卢克:哦,为什么?房子这么大,总不至于因为一个坏了的洗涤器而搬走吧.
Luke: Oh why, this is a great house don't you let a little broken washer chase you out.
外婆:哦,洗衣机也坏了?
Grandma: Oh the washers broken too?
卢克:不是,我是说水龙头那里的那个.很好修的.
Luke: No I meant the washer in the forset it's easy to fix.
外婆:我不觉得好修.
Grandma: Not for me,
埃德经常说我不中用,总是把东西搞坏.
Ed always said if there was a way to break a machine I'd find it,
他经常让我觉得自己没用.
he made me feel so helpless at times.
外公:唔,凯蒂,
Grandpa: Oh Kate I never wanted you to feel that way;
我可从没想过让你觉得没用;我只是有些不耐烦罢了,没别的意思.
I was just a little inpatient that's all.
哦,上帝,
Oh good lord now I know why they sent me back they wanted me to see
我知道他们为什么要我回来了.他们要让我知道我带给你多少烦恼.
what I've turned you into.
你是世界上最温柔,最美好的女人.我一直害怕这个世界.
The gentlest, sweetest woman I know, I've had afraid of the world.
卢克:外婆,请相信我,
Luke: Grandma Kate believe me changing the washer is a snap you just don't
换个水笼头是小菜一碟,你不用找西沃医生帮忙,
let doctor Sever help you, now come here let me show you how to do it,
我来教你.来吧.
come on.
这是进入房子的水管.拿着这个,
Now here's where the water enter the house,
你现在要做的是转这个,顺时针方向.
take this now all you have to do is turn this clockwise.
外婆:哦,我不知道.
Grandma: Oh I don't know.
外公:试一试,宝贝,你可以的.
Grandpa: Come on girl, you can do it.
外婆:顺时针方向.
Grandma: Clockwise.
卢克:顺时针方向.现在试一下,,
Luke: Clockwise, and now the test.Mrs.
马龙夫人,你刚才把水的伐门关上了.
Malone you just single handedly turn of the water .
外婆:哦,不.
Grandma: Oh no.
卢克:不,这很好啊.
Luke: No, that's good.
外婆:哦,天啊,我做到了.
Grandma: Oh boy, I did it.
外公:我知道你可以的.
Grandpa: I knew you could do it.
外婆:现在,让我再修修有毛病的玩意儿.
Grandma: Now, let me at that washer doohickey.
外婆:来呀,孩子们,谁要是最后一个到,谁就是烂苹果.
Grandma: Let's go everybody last one to the table is a rotten apple.
外公:是鸡蛋,凯蒂,哦,我想苹果也奏效.
Grandpa: Egg Kate well I guess apple would work.
麦琪:妈妈,你把什么都打开了?你打算干什么啊?
Maggie: Mom you unpacked everything, what's going on with you.
外婆:现在请你们坐好,我要向你们宣布一件事.
Grandma: If everyone will sit down I have an announcement.
我修好漏水管了.好,吃饭吧.
I fix the leaky forset.Now let's eat.
麦琪:妈妈,这就是你要宣布的事?
Maggie: Mom that's your announcement.
外婆:嗯,呃,还有,我不去佛罗里达了.
Grandma: Uh huh, oh ah and I'm not moving to Florida.
每个人:你不去了.
Everybody: You're not.
麦琪:可是,妈妈,
Maggie: But mom you have to you say yourself that this house was too much
你得去.你自己说这么大一个房子,你一个人收拾不了.
for you to handle.
外婆:不,这都是别人说的.
Grandma: No everyone else said it, the problem was I believed it,
问题在于我竟然相信了.我想留下来,因为这里有我一生的回忆.
I want to stay there's a life time of memories here.
麦琪:您说那是鬼魂.
Maggie: You call them ghost.
外婆:我喜欢鬼魂.
Grandma: I like the ghosts.
克莉丝:你留下来我真开心,外婆.
Chris: I'm glad you're staying grandma.
麦琪:哦,妈妈,我也是.
Maggie: Oh mom so am I.
外公:好宝贝,凯蒂.
Grandpa: Good girl Katie now my work here is done,
现在这里的事儿我做完了,如果快的话,没准还能赶上那场高尔夫球赛呢.
gee maybe if I hurry I could catch up with Scoraties on the back line.
本:午饭吃什么,外婆?
Ben: So what's for lunch grandma?
外婆:炝闷金枪鱼.这是埃德最爱吃的.
Grandma: Tuna casserole, it was Ed's favorite.
外公:哦,再放点土豆条,那味道就更好了.
Grandpa: Oh that's the one with the potato chips crumble on the top it's
真遗憾,我吃不成了.哦,算了,
a pity I can't eat anymore,
我还是等着在大师巡回赛上把迈克尔安吉洛收拾收拾吧.00:22:34,400
aw heck I'll just wait for the master tournament whip Michael Angelo's butt.